<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<welcomePage 
    title="Eclipse RSS Reader"
    format="wrap">

<intro><p>Publishing web-based news of all kinds via a summary format (RSS)
is becoming increasingly popular. The applications include regular headline 
news (Yahoo! News), web logs (Slashdot.org), professional bulletins 
(IBM developerWorks), and project updates (SourceForge.net). A variety of RSS 
formats currently exist, which increases application complexity. Often, a reader
capable of understanding one format cannot handle another. The Eclipse RSS 
Reader takes advantage of Eclipse platform in the following ways:</p>
<p>1. Extension points and plug-in based architecture support addition of new 
channel formats.</p>
<p>2. Workbench provides user interface consistency for users of existing 
Eclipse-based tools (I for one like to keep up-to-date while working in JDT).</p>
<p>3. Resource and UI model provides opportunities for integration with other 
Eclipse-based tools.</p>
</intro>

<item><b>Getting Started</b>
<p>1. Start your Workbench with a new or pre-existing workspace. Switch to the 
Resource perspective. If the workspace  is empty, create a new project.</p>
<p>2. In Resource Navigator, right-click on a folder and select New -&gt; RSS 
Channel.</p>
<p>3. Enter a URL for the RSS Channel; e.g., 
http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/news/dw_tech_nl.rss. Click "Load".</p>
<p>4. Select the default translator and click Next.</p>
<p>5. Enter a filename (with *.rss extension) and click Finish.</p>
<p>6. Select the newly created file in Resource Navigator. From the main menu, 
select Navigate -&gt; Show In -&gt; Channel  Navigator and/or Channel Detail.
</p>
<p>7. Browse and/or create channels in the Channel Navigator. Open the 
Properties view to see properties of selected  items. Double-click on selected 
items to read the channel or item link.</p>
</item>

<item><b>Features</b>
<p><b>1. Uniform channel model</b></p>
<p>RSS Feeds of various versions are coerced into a uniform channel model, 
which is persisted in the workspace. Third-party plug-ins may contribute 
"translators" for various channel formats. The default implementation handles  
RSS 0.90, 0.91, 0.92, 1.0, and 2.0. In case more than one registered translator 
understands a format, the user is given a choice to select one they wish to use.
In the future, annonymous elements external to the model will be exposed via 
untyped property interface (map), thus giving access to third-party plug-ins 
that may understand them.</p>

<p><b>2. Periodic updates</b></p>
<p>Based on user specification, channels are periodically updated from the 
source. All viewers are refreshed to display up-to-date information. In the 
future, markers will be used to identify changes and allow viewers to highlight 
them.</p>

<p><b>3. Property page</b></p>
<p>Individual channel files have a property page with RSS-specific options.</p>

<p><b>4. Preference page</b></p>
<p>Preference page allows the user to specify default values.</p>

<p><b>5. New Channel wizard</b></p>
<p>Allows users to create new channels from an external RSS feed source.</p>

<p><b>6. Channel Navigator</b></p>
<p>Allows users to navigate channels in container hierarchy.</p>

<p><b>7. Channel Detail view</b></p>
<p>Allows users to view details of selected channel.</p>

<p><b>8. Pluggable News Article Browsers</b></p>
<p>Users may choose how to view the contents of news articles. By default,
two methods are available: 1). Using the configured Help Browser, or 2).
Using a file editor that understands the article format (e.g., HTML).
In addition, users of WSAD running under MS-Windows have an option to use 
its Web Browser Editor. This option is specifiable on a per-channel basis.
3rd-party provides may offer additional methods via the provided extension 
point.</p>
</item>

<item><b>Learn more </b>
To learn more you can browse the
<topic id="/com.pnehrer.rss.doc.user/toc.xml">User Guide</topic> (TBD).</item>

</welcomePage>